

Curriculum Vitae for Thomas Peter Golding

Personal information

Address: Vekterveien 18B E-mail: thomas.golding@gmail.com

0681 Oslo Phone: +47 404 55 503

Born: 1985, June 2nd Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

Thomas is interested in bringing to life the potential of data for AI, automation and insight purposes. He will happily engage in the steps of such a process, from analysis and machine learning to data collection and software development. Thomas holds a PhD in astrophysics for developing and studying models of the solar atmosphere. After finishing the PhD he worked as an analyst in the public sector. Here he took part in the business intelligence process as well as data analyses, data modeling and system architecting. Thomas also completed the two year leadership development program Teach First Norway. The varied experience makes Thomas a diverse problem solver with a critical and systematic approach. He has the ability of quickly adopting to new projects and suggest novel solutions.

Technical skills

Frameworks Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Keras, Tensorflow, Spark

Languages Python, R, SQL, IDL, C, Fortan, Qlik
Tools Git, CVS, Confluence, Jira, RStudio, Latex

Education

2012 – 2017 PhD in astrophysics, UiO. Physical processes in the solar atmosphe-

re. The work included building mathematical and numerical representiontions of the physical system. The numerical model served as an experiment and a basis for analysis. Research results were published

in scientific journals and presented at conferences.

2010 – 2011 Teacher qualification, UiO. Training to be a maths and science teacher

in secondary and upper secondary school.

2005 – 2010 Master of science in astrophysics, UiO. Numerical modelling of the

solar atmosphere. Physics, maths and computer science on bachelor

level.

Professional experience

2019 – Consultant, Expert analytics

2019 - 2019 Consultant, Accenture. Google cloud platform, big data and BI busi-

ness analysis.

2016 – 2018 Analyst, Statens pensjonskasse. Business intelligence, forecasting, in-

surance mathematics, software development, data warehousing and

database design.

2010 – 2012 Teach First Norway candidate. A two year teacher and leadership

development program for graduates.

Languages

English fluent

Norwegian mother tongue

Some interests and hobbies

Personal playing music, news and podcasts

Technology machine learning, natural language processing, programming

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity New pension premium system at Statens pensionskasse

Period 04/2017-09/2017

Role Developer for a premium forecast model

Staffing 3 developers and 7 analysts

Volume 50%

Description The organization was moving a large part of their customers to a new

pension premium system. How the premiums were computed changed, and this had consequences for a large part of the organization. Thomas was responsible for developing the premium forecast system. He built a mathematical description of the model and implemented in a computer program. He designed the data flow and automated data queries. The

various components were built into a software package.

Tools R, SQL, Jira

Activity Building a data pipeline at Statens pensjonskasse

Period 10/2017-01/2018

Role Developer and architect

Staffing 2 developers

Volume 50%

Description Thomas identified a bottle neck in one of the organization's central

processes. He suggested, designed, implemented and saw through the realization of a data pipeline for data from different sub processes. The solution included new software for the transform and load of business data, as well as a centralized data base for storage. The project presented a unification of data from the relevant sub processes into one standard data model. The solution resulted in higher efficiency

and paved the way for future automation.

Tools R, SQL, Jira

Activity PhD - numerical modeling of the solar atmosphere

Period 08/2012-02/2017

Description Thomas studied how time dependent atomic processes affect the tem-

perature and overall state of the solar atmosphere. To do this he developed a mathematical description of the problem and translated it into a computer algorithm. He implemented the algorithm in a parallel computer code for simulating the sun. Numerical models were produced by running the code on supercomputers. The numerical models were used to analyse interaction between solar gas and light. In particular how temperature and ability to emit light changed due to the time dependent atomic process. The efforts resulted in four academic papers in the project, three of these as the first author. All four papers

were published in peer-reviewed journals.

Tools Fortran, IDL, Python, Latex

Activity Business intelligence development at Statens pensjonskasse

Period 06/2016-12/2018 Role Qlikview development

Staffing 3 developers

Volume 20%

Description Statens pensionskasse is continuously working on development and

improvements of their automated reports. Thomas worked on mapping out business needs and suggested solutions in the datawarehouse. He

also worked on report development in QlikView and QlikSense.

Tools R, Qlikview, Qliksense, Jira

Activity Business intelligence development

Period 04/2019-08/2019 Role Business analyst

Staffing Project manager, business analyst and 5 developers

Volume 100%

Description Thomas acted as a bridge between business and technical develop-

ment. He mapped out business needs and requirements, wrote technical specifications and performed administrative tasks related to the

operation.

Tools Qlikview, Qliksense, SAS, Jira, Python

Activity Teach First Norway candidate

Period 07/2010-06/2012

Description Candidates work as teachers in challenging schools in Oslo at the

same time as they are following a demanding development and training program. The program revolves around the pupil's learning outcome through the candidate's progress as teachers and leaders. Thomas worked 2 years as a teacher in Gran skole at Furuset in Oslo. Here he taught maths and science from 4th-10th grade (10-16 year). Simultaneously he completed formal teacher training the first year and a

leadership program at Equinor the second year.